

CONTACT INFO

Phone: +52 81-34-16-03-85 García, Nuevo León, MEX. rolando.code@gmail.com

LANGUAGE

Spanish

English

EXPERTISE

Net Framework
Dapper
EF and EF Core
Dot Net core
Dot Net 5, 6
ASP Net Core 8
MS SQL Server
GIT
Typescript
Angular

MORE ABOUT ME



You can visit my portfolio scanning the QR. https://bit.ly/rdom-page

Rolando Domínguez

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER/ TECH LEAD

SUMMARY

I am a software developer with 10 years of experience, who enjoys backend development with .NET technology and Angular on the client side. I love writing clean code, it's a fully creative activity and a whole art. I feel passionate when applications are built and deployed successfully in cloud environments. Creating open-source applications, that help me daily and could help others is one of my favorite hobbies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Coherent Solutions- Full stack developer & Tech lead

2023- Present

<u>Full stack developer and Tech Lead at WEX client.</u> **Dotnet and angular** integrations with TPA vendors, Angular migration from version 6 to 8, **MS SQL** script database enhancements with over 1,000 tables (SP, Views, functions, etc), **Micro frontend** enhancements, support to legacy systems in **VB ASP Web Forms.** As tech lead: **API Rest** designs and **architectural concepts**, **PR reviews**, tech training and **coaching** support, proof of concepts for new APIs, **user stories definitions** with PO, **production deployment** staff, technical staff recruiter.

AGILE THOUGHT- Dot net Senior and consultant developer

2021-2023

- <u>Senior software engineer at Brierley client.</u> 2021-2022 **Net framework** code maintenance. **REST API conversion** from SOAP. Code enhancements and **code reviews in GitHub. Oracle DB** scripts.
- <u>Senior software engineer at VyStar client</u>. 2022-2023. **Net core** code maintenance. **ASP Net MVC pages** refactors and maintenance. Net core **small modules migration to net 6**. Using of MS **Azure pipelines**

AXOSNET- Net core, Net framework and Angular Sr. developer

2019-2021

Net framework to Net core 3.1 migration (from scratch. Invoice verification software **API design and creation** for México, Costa Rica, Colombia, and Perú Internal tools in **Angular and AngularJS. Technical designs** for API solutions in **net framework/core** and **SQL server**. AWS **cloudwatch**, **EC2** instances, load balancers

Bind ERP- Technical and software support lead. Semi Sr. developer 2018-2019

APIs Rest and Web Services integration for Mexican invoicing. Technical staff recruiter. ASP Net and Web forms migrations to AngularJS and Typescript. Microsoft Azure app services settings and deployments

Bind ERP – Jr. dot Net Framework and AngularJS developer

2015-2018

SQL server production DB management. Computer building and maintenance, local network configuration. Support app creation with **AngularJS** with **Typescript** and **Net Framework**.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Master's degree in Information Technology Engineering

2016-2018

School of mechanical and electrical engineering. UANL.

Computer Science degree

2010-2015

School of Physics and Mathematics UANL

CERTIFICATES

- Using SOLID principles to Write Better Code
- Creating professional web APIs with .NET 6
- Software Engineering 101: Use Software Engineering to Plan and Build Amazing Software + Learn SCRUM Framework!

GitHub projects

https://github.com/orgs/OpenSourceRvProjects/repositories https://github.com/orgs/My-Proffesional-Portfolio/repositories